<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Enrico&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Enrico&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Enrico Spinielli</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://enrico.spinielli.net/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing a Twitter Bot in R</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2018/06/30/writing-a-twitter-bot-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2018/06/30/writing-a-twitter-bot-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Since a while I am contemplating the possibility of automatically publishing on social media some stats and data visualisations from work.
When I discovered the nice bot @everytract by @fitnr (and a little later the @GVAcartografic’s #Secciócensal tweets) I decided to try and do a Twitter bot myself in order to see what is possible and how difficult it is.
I thought that combining maps and some Italian data would be a good recipe for having fun and so I did set out to use some GIS data from the Italian National Institute of Statistics (ISTAT)(@istat_en) in order to publish a map for every Italian comune (the basic administrative division in Italy).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ErgoDox keyboard</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2018/01/03/ergodox-keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2018/01/03/ergodox-keyboard/</guid>
      <description>Now that I have a new blog setup, I can more quickly post what has been since long time in the making: my ErgoDox keyboard.
It all started with me reading Steve Yegge’s blog on touch typing and being convinced I should give it a try with a proper keyboard.
So on 2014-03-24 I joined a Massdrop purchase for an DIY ErgoDox split keyboard. It completed a week later and delivery was done somewhat end of May.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Blog Engine</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2018/01/02/new-blog-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2018/01/02/new-blog-engine/</guid>
      <description>I finally decided to give it a try and then switched to blogdown (here the free book.)
I sort of followed the migration suggestions in the book, but when I tried to switch to Netlify I got everyting messed up with my OVH setup so I am still with Github Pages…one step at a time…
I hope this setup will lower the barrier and allow me to blog and share more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker image for locally testing Oracle</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2016/10/31/docker-image-for-locally-testing-oracle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2016/10/31/docker-image-for-locally-testing-oracle/</guid>
      <description>Docker for Oracle This post describes my journey to building and using a docker image for Oracle.
It all started as usual searching the web for hints and many results led to the Oracle docker Github repository.
This repository under OracleDatabase provides (almost) all the informations needed.
My target machine: MacBook Pro (13-inch, Mid 2009), OS X Yosemite 10.10.5.
Which Oracle RDBMS? I decided to use Oracle XE 11.2.0.2 because my use case just needed an Oracle DB, so no need to go for bigger and fancier versions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting C.H.I.P. up</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2016/08/07/setting-c-h-i-p-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2016/08/07/setting-c-h-i-p-up/</guid>
      <description>Few weeks ago I finally received my C.H.I.P. and PocketC.H.I.P.
C.H.I.P. is the famous $9 computer crowdfunded in May 2015 via Kickstarter and PowerC.H.I.P. combines a 4.3-inch screen and a button-style QWERTY keypad with it.
Here they are in all their beauty:
   C.H.I.P. Pocket C.H.I.P.          Setting C.H.I.P. up I am interested to play with both toys remotely, so I did follow Setting up CHIP as a headless server with minimal tools in order to install and configure ssh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DVD to Android Tablet</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2016/04/02/dvd2tablet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2016/04/02/dvd2tablet/</guid>
      <description>How to transfer your DVDs to your Android Tablet Suppose your kids want to watch their DVDs in the car on their Android tablet&amp;hellip;
Here is what you can do (on a Mac OSX 10.9.5):
 install Handbrake and its CLI   $ brew cask install handbrake $ brew cask install handbrakecli   install libdvdcss (thanks to lifehacker&amp;rsquo;s article) in order to bypass copy protection   $ brew install libdvdcss   go to the place where you will place the ripped DVD:   $ cd ~/Movies   convert your DVDs:   $ HandBrakeCLI -i /Volumes/&#39;my DVD&#39; -o /Volumes/Untitled/Movies/my_dvd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Vega 2.0 a.k.a. Reactive Vega</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2015/08/08/learning-reactive-vega/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2015/08/08/learning-reactive-vega/</guid>
      <description>h1 ~ aside { font-size: small; right: 0; position: absolute; width: 180px; }  A Grammar of Graphics Vega 2.0 adds a grammar of interaction to the grammar of graphics implemented in Vega 1.0.
When you say grammar of graphics all roads bring you to
 Leland Wilkinson The Grammar of Graphics Springer Science &amp;amp; Business Media, Jul 15, 2005
 But given the price of 100+ USD, I am not even thinking of getting my hands on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to add a new chart type to dc.js</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2015/04/21/how-to-add-a-new-chart-type-to-dcjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 17:56:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2015/04/21/how-to-add-a-new-chart-type-to-dcjs/</guid>
      <description>This is a step by step description of how I extended dc.js with a new chart type. It is inspired by a wiki page by Thomas Robert.
A Bullet chart Mike Bostock already implemented a bullet chart in D3.js. The vertical version from Jason Davies uses the official code which is available as a d3-plugin. (I have submitted a proposal for a bug fix and will use it instead.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML Scraping or Surviving Orrible Corporate Tools</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2015/02/07/html-scraping/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2015/02/07/html-scraping/</guid>
      <description>At work I have to fill my weekly timesheet. We use Planisware&amp;rsquo;s Timecard to record time spent on the various projects we are assigned to work on.
So you need to known what the total working time is for the day. For that our badging in and out is recorded and passed to Chronogestor which does sums them up and provides both a sexagesimal and decimal format.
When there is an anomaly the sums are blocked till the request you submitted to fix it is implemented&amp;hellip; So I thought I could do some web scraping and extract my clockings from the relevant CG&amp;rsquo;s page, make the total for the day (in decimal form: in Timecard we record time in decimal form, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Internet Long Tail Helped Me Fixing My Smartphone</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2015/01/30/how-internet-long-tail-helped-me-fixing-my-smartphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2015/01/30/how-internet-long-tail-helped-me-fixing-my-smartphone/</guid>
      <description>I am just more and more amazed by the opportunities offered by the current Internet connectivity: they call it the long tail.
It strikes me that just few years ago what I have done would have been extreemely difficult or very expensive &amp;hellip; or both.
 So here is the story of how I was able to fix my Samsung Galaxy S2, the steps I followed and the resources that helped me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Great Circle Arcs Intersection Algorithm</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2014/10/19/understanding-great-circle-arcs_57/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2014/10/19/understanding-great-circle-arcs_57/</guid>
      <description>The following material is the result of my attempt to understand the nice example from Jason Davies. I was puzzled about the origin of the algorithm used to find the intersection of two great circle arcs. Google helped and I discovered Roger Stafford&amp;rsquo;s post in Matlab newsgroup and the relevant Python&amp;rsquo;s implementation in the Spherical Geometry Toolkit.
The algorithm You have two great circle arcs on a sphere, $a$ from point $\mathbf{a_0}$ to $\mathbf{a_1}$, and $b$ from $\mathbf{b_0}$ to $\mathbf{b_1}$, whose coordinates are expressed as longitude $\theta$ (positive going East of Greenwich) and latitude $\phi$ (positive going North).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Failing to be recruited...</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2014/08/29/impressions-about-selection-process-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2014/08/29/impressions-about-selection-process-of/</guid>
      <description>This post title to be frank should have been &amp;ldquo;Impressions about the selection process of a big Internet company (and my failure to go to the next steps after initial engagement),&amp;rdquo; but that is obviously too long.
So I only kept the failure part with the aim to bring home some lessons from it ! 😏
Chronology, more or less It all started with an email at the end of July 2014 from the company&amp;rsquo;s recruiter, let&amp;rsquo;s call her Alice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>on revising</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2013/05/13/on-revising/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2013/05/13/on-revising/</guid>
      <description>Lately I found myself involved into writing. And I have been often cought into the vicious cycle of revising my (or other&#39;s) text without really understanding how to do it properly and when to stop. I want to summarize some of the advise I found on the web. I put it here for me to find it again and share. Let&#39;s first paraphrase the famous grook from Piet Hein: THE ROAD TO WRITING?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatically extracting bomb drops from the Blitz Bomb Census maps</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2012/05/19/automatically-extracting-bomb-drops/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2012/05/19/automatically-extracting-bomb-drops/</guid>
      <description>I just finished Blackout by Connie Willis&amp;nbsp;and I was wondering where she did get all the exact times when the air raids of The Blitz were happening.
I am curious because I was thinking that a timeline map would give a visual effect of the huge destruction and hard times the Londoners had to go through...so I googled for it and found the following:
a nice research blog&amp;nbsp;which uses the Blitz Bomb Census from The National Archivesa blog entry from the Guardian about the first day - and data - of the Blitz over London.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>wiki of the future?</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2012/04/19/wiki-of-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2012/04/19/wiki-of-future/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend I have been watching, reading and playing around with Ward Cunningham&#39;s Smallest Federated Wiki. As usual he is a great designer and aims to simple, effective, understandable and useful tools! I particularly like the plugins idea (not new of course) and how easy it seems to be to add new ones, like support for MathJax:  Get inspired you too!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>metacircularity</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2012/04/18/metacircularity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2012/04/18/metacircularity/</guid>
      <description>I found and liked a very good summary of the &amp;lsquo;Maxwell Equations of software&amp;rsquo; motto from Alan Kay in this post from Michael Nielsen.
It is nice also because it has running code inspired by all the gurus and books I like: Alan Kay, Peter Norvig, John McCarthy, SICP, Paul Graham.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>syntax highlight</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2012/04/18/this-code-shows-how-to-syntax-highligh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2012/04/18/this-code-shows-how-to-syntax-highligh/</guid>
      <description>The following example shows how to syntax highligh some snippet of code in a very minimalistic way.
I used it by symlinking to a file in the version control repo and name it in as the argument of
$(&#39;#code-area&#39;).load() and here it is: 

code higlighted with minimal javascript







Metacircular code highlighting
The following code is an highlighted version of this very page using</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git and RSA identities</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2012/02/06/git-and-rsa-identities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2012/02/06/git-and-rsa-identities/</guid>
      <description>Here is the solution I found to be able to use git with a different RSA identity than the rsa_id default one.
My repo on github is logback-android and my user account is espinielli.
I did generate an SSH key as per github help and named it github_rsa:
$ ssh-keygen -t rsa -C &#34;your_email@youremail.com&#34; -f github_rsa
I then added the following section in ~/.ssh/config
# github for espinielli
Host github</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LaTeX on Blogger again</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2012/01/20/latex-on-blogger-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2012/01/20/latex-on-blogger-again/</guid>
      <description>MathJax.Hub.Config({tex2jax: {inlineMath: [[&#39;$&#39;,&#39;$&#39;], [&#39;\\(&#39;,&#39;\\)&#39;]]}});  My previous post&amp;nbsp;about&amp;nbsp;LaTeX&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;on Blogger&amp;nbsp;reported that the solution described there did not work anymore...
Now I found a new solution based on mathjax.
So let&#39;s try it straight away with inline math, like the great equation \(e^{-2\pi}\), and with displayed math like the following:
\[ \left [ - \frac{\hbar^2}{2 m} \frac{\partial^2}{\partial x^2} + V \right ] \Psi
= i \hbar \frac{\partial}{\partial t} \Psi \]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(What was) Croquet is maybe still alive</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2011/03/26/what-was-croquet-is-maybe-still-alive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2011/03/26/what-was-croquet-is-maybe-still-alive/</guid>
      <description>It seems there is still some hope to see Croquet (or, OpenCobalt which took off from where Croquet stopped) alive and based on latest Squeak and more importantly using Cog VM.
Matthew Fulmer reports it here.
The potentials are magical as explained by Howard Stearns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating Pier</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2010/10/31/investigating-pier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2010/10/31/investigating-pier/</guid>
      <description>I have been playing around with Pier.
It is fun, especially when you can extend it to show LaTeX formulae (this is still work in progress given I am using the js from MathJax [even if forbidden], but hey I wanted a proof of concept!)
I will try to complete it: whatch out &amp;lsquo;Beautiful Math for Pier&amp;rsquo; on squeaksource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LaTeX on Blogger</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2009/11/11/text-on-latex-snippet-in-blogger-from/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2009/11/11/text-on-latex-snippet-in-blogger-from/</guid>
      <description>An inline snippet of LaTeX \(e^{\pi i}+1=0\) in blogger (from http://watchmath.com/vlog/?p=438 but it now, Oct 2010, shows crap!).
You can as well have it in display style \[e^{\pi i}+1=0\].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geomapping: what a wonderful world!</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2009/10/27/geomapping-what-wonderful-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2009/10/27/geomapping-what-wonderful-world/</guid>
      <description>Suppose you have a set of lat/lon points, where do you find out their elevation?
Simple, let say you have the following coordinates (a cross in concrete on the top of the hill in front of my parents&amp;rsquo; place):
45.469678, 10.970527 (I got these from &#39;Get Directions from here&#39; in google maps)  Then call the relevant USGS&amp;rsquo; web service
It says
getElevation for Latitude 45.46 --&amp;gt; Y_Value=45.469678 for Longitude 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyCalCal is out!</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2009/10/26/pycalcal-is-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2009/10/26/pycalcal-is-out/</guid>
      <description>I finally set to put PyCalCal out in the open.
I will need to finalize and perfect it but that is a good starting point.
I also added a demo web app using it.
My idea is for PyCalCal to be used as a Python library and as such use it to provide calendrica calculations as web services.
Stay tuned if you are interested.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giants&#39; Shoulders in music</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2009/07/28/giants-shoulders-in-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2009/07/28/giants-shoulders-in-music/</guid>
      <description>A nice song about a great Giant, Galileo, by the Chromatics.
Read text and listen to music, here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scons and noweb</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2009/06/14/scons-and-noweb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2009/06/14/scons-and-noweb/</guid>
      <description>I was curious to see how I could integrate noweb and Scons.
You can download my little Sconstruct for this, Sconstruct.example. It defines two builders. NoWeave is used to produce TeX or LaTeX documents, while NoTangle extracts the non-document artefacts, i.e. programs, config files, scripts &amp;hellip; It also includes productions for generating a sample program about Ackermann function:
ackdoc = env.NoWeave(&amp;#39;ack.tex&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;ack.nw&amp;#39;) ackcode = env.NoTangle(&amp;#39;ack.py&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;ack.nw&amp;#39;) acktest = env.NoTangle(&amp;#39;ackTest.py&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;ack.nw&amp;#39;) The noweb source is ack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LaTeX, Python and Literate Programming</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2009/02/24/latex-python-and-literate-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2009/02/24/latex-python-and-literate-programming/</guid>
      <description>In my spare time (a couple of hours per weekend&amp;hellip;!) I am implementing calcal, a Python version of calendrica-3.0.cl, the Common Lisp implementation of the calendars from N. Dershowitz, E. M. Reingold Calendrical Calculations, 3rd Edition. (In case you are interested you can find a preview in my github repo.)
At some point I decided to go Literate Programming using noweb. This is an experiment in the experiment but so far it has been a good choice because I can define all I need in the same place and generate documentation, source code (Python, shell scripts &amp;hellip;) from the same source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Giants</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2009/02/23/my-giants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2009/02/23/my-giants/</guid>
      <description>I am probably too selective, anyway my models for computer science/software engineering (one of them would disagree on both definitions) are just two: Donald E. Knuth and Alan Kay.
The first one continues to surprise me with the depth, clarity and joy of his works: from TeX (well, I use LaTex but it does not exist without TeX) to The Art of Computer Programming to Literate Programming.
About the latter, I was one of the blessed to be present to his Turing Award Lecture: he shocked me to the point I had two sleepless nights so angry I was about having wasted so much time in useless (computer) matters!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>