<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Javascript on Enrico&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/tags/javascript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Javascript on Enrico&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Enrico Spinielli</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 17:56:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://enrico.spinielli.net/tags/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to add a new chart type to dc.js</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2015/04/21/how-to-add-a-new-chart-type-to-dcjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 17:56:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2015/04/21/how-to-add-a-new-chart-type-to-dcjs/</guid>
      <description>This is a step by step description of how I extended dc.js with a new chart type. It is inspired by a wiki page by Thomas Robert.
A Bullet chart Mike Bostock already implemented a bullet chart in D3.js. The vertical version from Jason Davies uses the official code which is available as a d3-plugin. (I have submitted a proposal for a bug fix and will use it instead.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>wiki of the future?</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2012/04/19/wiki-of-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2012/04/19/wiki-of-future/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend I have been watching, reading and playing around with Ward Cunningham&#39;s Smallest Federated Wiki. As usual he is a great designer and aims to simple, effective, understandable and useful tools! I particularly like the plugins idea (not new of course) and how easy it seems to be to add new ones, like support for MathJax:  Get inspired you too!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>syntax highlight</title>
      <link>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2012/04/18/this-code-shows-how-to-syntax-highligh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://enrico.spinielli.net/2012/04/18/this-code-shows-how-to-syntax-highligh/</guid>
      <description>The following example shows how to syntax highligh some snippet of code in a very minimalistic way.
I used it by symlinking to a file in the version control repo and name it in as the argument of
$(&#39;#code-area&#39;).load() and here it is: 

code higlighted with minimal javascript







Metacircular code highlighting
The following code is an highlighted version of this very page using</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>